# **RUSIRU THUSHARA**

🔁 <u>thusharakart@gmail.com</u> 🕴 372/1, Opalla, Govinna, Horana, Sri Lanka 🔍 +94 71 302 2214

📵 <u>rusiru.me</u> 📊 linkedin/rusiru-thushara 🔛 <u>github/thusharakart</u> 🕩 <u>hackerrank/thusharakart</u>

## **PROFILE**

A 3rd-year computer engineering undergraduate with five national level hackathon wins since 2019 and over two years of software development in Java and Python. A quick learner with a strong interest in algorithmic programming, artificial intelligence and a passion for finding simple, innovative solutions to complex programming problems and seeking an opportunity in a challenging environment for an internship to contribute towards the organization and team growth.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Nov. 2017 - Present

Undergraduate in BSc. Engineering(Hons.) Computer Engineering CGPA: 3.80/4.00

SPARK X Professional Development Program | Spark Academy, Sri Lanka

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

A 6-month industry readiness program for software engineers that includes technical modules like developing and delivering real-world applications, creative problem solving, and soft skills like empathy, communication, leadership, professionalism, and ethics. Earned a full Spark Academy scholarship during the selection process.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Co-Founder and Software Team Lead | SternX Engineering (Pvt) Limited

March 2021 - Present

Team leader of an eight-member software developer team who follows Scrum methodologies to deliver web and mobile applications for clients.

## Instructor and Teaching Assistant | University of Peradeniya

2020 - Present

CO321: Embedded Systems for 3rd year Computer Engineering undergraduates

CO253: Programming and Networking for Electrical and Electronic Engineering undergraduates

GP106: Computing for all first year undergraduates

#### **SKILLS**

Languages	Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript	Backend	Spring Boot, Nodejs, Expressjs, Django
Mobile Development	Native Android, Flutter	Frontend	Reactjs, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB	Modeling	TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

1st Runner up of Douthan 1.0 (of 80+ teams)	Feb. 2021
12 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.	
1st, 2nd, 1st Country Rank in Hack the Interview IV,V,VI (Asia Pacific)	2020
60 hours competitive coding contest on hackerrank	
Placed 1st, 2nd, 1st country rank and 88/4353, 343/3077, 195/2530 respectively in Asia Pacific region	
2nd Runner up of HackDown 2020 (of 200+ teams)   Competitive programming competition	Apr. 2020
2nd Runner up of hackStat 2.0 (of 90+ teams)	Oct. 2019

Competition in data analysis and prediction on an insurance data set.

-		· ·	-				
2nd	Runner up	of UoJCode	ers v1.0	(of 10	0+ tear	ns)	March 2019
_							

Competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka. Top 20 country rank of IEEEXtreme 14.0 (of 2000+ global teams)

Top 20 country rank of IEEEXtreme 14.0 (of 2000+ global teams)	Oct. 2020
24 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates worldwide.	

1680th global rank of Facebook Hacker Cup 2020 (of 32500+ global participants) July 2020

2019 - 2020 Top 20 country rank of Google Code Jam, Hash Code, Kick Start Gold Medal in Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad | National Rank - 2nd, Score: 96/100 2016

An annual competition held among high school students to select delegations for the APhO and IPhO.

## **PROJECTS**

Identity Access Management (IAM) System for University of Peradeniya  Defining and managing the roles and access privileges of individual network entities of the UoP.  Technologies: Express.js, React.js, Web Security, Authentication, Authorization	Ongoin
National Covid 19 Management System Full-stack web application showcasing country level, district level, hospital level, and overall patien statistics of daily Covid-19 updates and the patient management system. Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Spring Security, React, PostgreSQL	202 nt
Swarm Robots Platform  Obstacle bots that are localized with an overhead camera setup with the capability of positioning themselves without collisions forming challenging patterns.  Technologies: Django, OpenCV, Numpy, Three.js, CSS, HTML, MQTT, GRPC  Techniques: Stochastic gradient descent, PID, Image processing, Encryption	202 ng
Project MESOW A portable device for the visually impaired, which is getting a video stream of the surrounding, analyse at and sends a real-time acknowledgment of the surrounding via voice. Technologies: Python, OpenCV, Numpy, AI, NLP	Ongoin es
Airport Ticket Booking System Web application and Mobile Application with a Database Management System for passengers and airpo Technologies: Dart, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS	202 orts.
<b>Crossword Puzzle Game</b> An instant game developed for Facebook focusing children where they can select and solve a crosswor Technologies: <b>React.js</b>	202 d puzzle.
<b>Auction Server</b> Implemented a sample server that can be used by clients to bid for items in a stock exchange. Technologies: Java   Techniques: Threads, Synchronization primitives, Sockets, OOP, and Collections	201
CERTIFICATES AND COURSES	
Introduction to Cybersecurity   Cisco Networking Academy	Jan. 202
Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization   UC San Diego   Coursera	202
Deep Learning Specialization   deeplearning.ai   Coursera	202
Al for Medicine Specialization   deeplearning.ai   Coursera	202
AWS Computer Vision: Getting started with GluonCV   AWS   Coursera	202
Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching	2019 - 202
Routing and Switching Essentials, Introduction to Networks   Cisco Networking Academy	
Fundamentals of Business Economics   Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA)	May 201
EXTRA CURRICULAR	
Teaching Data Structures and algorithms with Hackers' Club for all undergraduates at UoP	202
Creating coding problems for five HackerRank programming competitions of UoP <a href="https://github.com/thusharakart/Coding-Sessions">https://github.com/thusharakart/Coding-Sessions</a>	202
Volunteer teaching   Maths, Science and English at Omaththa College, Mathugama	2019 - 202
Captain   Main Chess Team, Taxila Central College, Horana, Sri Lanka Have won multiple achievements including 1st runner-up in district level	2008 - 201
Senior House Captain   Taxila Central College, Horana, Sri Lanka	201
REFERENCE	

Prof. Roshan Ragel roshanr@pdn.ac.lk Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering, Univeristy of Peradeniya

Dr. Isuru Nawinne <u>isurunawinne@eng.pdn.ac.lk</u> Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering, Univeristy of Peradeniya